[Music]
Hello everyone, welcome back to
another great lesson here at English.
Hot, my name is Marco.
My name is Katherine, hello everyone.
And today we've got a great lesson
for you at the upper intermediate level.
We're going to be talking about an
interesting topic, which is gambling.
Yeah, I don't know if you like
to do this Marco go, you know.
I'm actually going to play some cards,
play some poker, blackjack, throw the dice.
I'm actually a bit of
a fan of the roulette.
You have to throw the
ball onto the wheel that's
spinning and lands into like a
little compartment in a number.
Right, so you can win like based
on the number and the color.
But it's interesting
because if you get the
number right, it pays
you 35 times your bet.
Wow, that's a lot of money to win.
A lot of potential there was a
lot of numbers on that wheel.
But that's the thing, some people
like gambling, some people don't like it.
And in some countries, in
some states, it's illegal, right?
Exactly.
So today we're talking about a city
that's looking to legalize this sport.
So we're going to take
a listen here at one time.
We come back.
We're talking all about
what's going on today's lesson.
Did you hear the state is thinking
of legalizing gambling in our city?
Soon we're going to
have amazing hotels and
casinos here, which
would be good for business.
Are you serious?
Gambling is a vice industry built on
deception and fed by the intentional
exploitation of human weakness
for the sole purpose of monetary gain.
It disgusts me.
What are you talking about?
How does it exploit people?
Well, to begin with, gambling is addictive.
It ruins marriages, destroys
families, and bankrupts communities.
Once you're addicted,
it's very difficult to stop.
People have lost their
houses, cars, and have been
left out on the street
after becoming addicted.
Secondly, it exploits because
men become addicted to
gambling most often
because of the action and risk.
Women gamble to escape, and senior citizens
will start gambling for social interaction.
Under age gamblers
often start gambling on
sports with friends
and then illegal bookies.
Jeez.
Now that I think about it, maybe
legalizing gambling isn't such a good idea.
Although I have been
to Las Vegas, and I
didn't become addicted
or anything like that.
You cannot predict who will
be committed to gambling.
Now, excuse me, I have a
protest value to organize.
All right, so a very strong
opinion against gambling, right?
Absolutely, so we've got someone
who hasn't really thought it through.
And another person who has thought
way too much about what's going on, right?
And well, he did point out some very
interesting arguments against gambling.
And so we're going to
take a look at some of the
language that person used
today in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Well, this first what
we've got here is a word
that has to do with the
topic of today's lesson.
So legalizing gambling,
what does it mean to legalize?
Right, so to legalize, to make it legal.
So legal is the word that refers to law.
And so that means to make something okay,
it means to allow something
in a state or country.
Exactly. So in many
countries, it's illegal to gamble.
So in this case, the city is looking
to legalize it to make it legal.
All right, so many young people in
America would like to see this law changed.
You're not allowed to drink until
your 21 years old drink alcohol that is.
So they would like to see the
legalization of underage drinking.
Now, is it 21 in all states or
in the majority of all states?
I thought it was only in some of them.
Now, it changed in
the late 70s, I think, but
you absolutely cannot
drink until your 21.
Wow. What do you think?
Is that okay or is that?
I think that it encourages young
people to drink irresponsibly.
And so I believe we should legalize
drinking at the age of 18 because it would
make people learn how
to be more responsible.
All right. Interesting. All right.
So we want to legalize
underage drinking English fun.
All right. Now, let's not
manipulate my words,
but this next word is
very, very important.
He's saying that gambling or the
gambling industry exploits people.
Okay, exploit. You might have
heard this in the news before.
We talk about often in the
news, the exploitation of people.
But in this case, we're
talking about, yeah,
exploiting people through
money and gambling.
Right. So to exploit basically
is to take advantage of them.
Right. To use them for
something, not to treat them
as people, but to use them
as a way to get something.
All right. So we often
hear about it as you're
saying news about,
you know, factories or
companies exploiting their
employees or something of the sort.
We can also exploit the
earth for its resources
by taking oil and taking
diamonds and taking gold.
Okay. So to take advantage of interesting.
So to exploit is the verb,
but exploitation is the now.
All right. That's the thing.
So we talk about the exploitation of
people in this country or
the exploitation of the earth.
And they're talking about how gambling
exploits people and how it's a vice.
Ooh, vices. So for those of
you, a Christian's out there,
you might be very
familiar with the sins, right?
The seven deadly sins. Well, these are
all vices, things that you do that are bad.
So drinking too much is a vice.
Right. Or eating too much, right?
All right. Or spending money without
having money, maybe a vice for you.
So addictions are also
a type of vice, right?
Like drinking,
smoking, or drug abuse.
Exactly. These are all vices.
So vice is a bad thing.
Now we often now we may remember this show
popular American show called Miami vice.
So what is that?
Well, Miami vice, it's in the city of
Miami and it's about police officers.
So in the police, there's sometimes
a group called the vice squad.
These are people who
go out and try and stop
people who are doing
things that are vices.
Oh, like drugs and gambling.
Yeah, exactly.
Vice squad. Interesting. All right.
And now for the last word on language,
take away.
We have this interesting word, a bookie.
All right. So if any of you
like to go to the horse races,
you might be familiar with this one. A
bookie is someone who helps you make a bet.
It's his job to help you make a bet.
Mm-hmm. So we often see it in movies.
Maybe you are betting on
a sports competition, right?
And you are betting on
around $10 against this team.
So you would go to a
bookie to place your bet,
because there's not really any
legal place where you can do it.
Exactly. Or if I want to say, okay,
tonight, the Chicago Bulls are playing the
sons and you want to put
$100 on the Chicago Bulls.
That means they're going to win.
So you use a bookie and he
helps you put the money down.
Now, usually this is illegal, right?
Generally, it's illegal.
Yeah, it depends.
I guess you can go to a bookie
at the horse races in a legal bet.
But generally
it's illegal, I think.
Okay. So a sports bookie, we
would say a sports bookie, right?
Yeah. Interesting
words. A lot of words
related to, as we said,
addictions and vices,
but that's, I guess, kind of what the
whole gambling industry involves, right?
Absolutely. All right.
So now that we've seen
those great words on
language, take away,
let's move on now to fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Okay. Fluency builders
where we get into some
of this really exciting
stuff stuff where we
hear some opinions from a person who is
not very happy with the gambling industry.
So this first one, gambling is
an industry built on deception.
Okay. So it's built
on deception.
So well, it's an industry.
So it's not really tangible.
Right. So this is a
metaphor. It's like saying
that this industry is
dependent on something.
And what does it depend on? Deception.
Deception. So what's deception?
So to deceive, right?
They come from the verb
deceive, which basically says
like a false appearance, right?
Not really being
completely truthful.
Okay. So it's really good.
So a lot of movies that
we like to watch or theater
is based on deception
in a good way because
you get the idea that
something is a certain way,
but it really isn't in real life.
So deception is is in a theater,
maybe a good thing. But in
general, deception is a bad thing.
I could say Marco, I'm
sorry, I deceived you.
Well, you lied to me.
I lied to you. Yeah. So
deception usually involves lies or
trying to make something
seem like something that it's not.
Right. Okay. So it's this industry is
built on deception. And he said that the
sole purpose of this
industry is to make money.
Exactly. So this, this phrase, sole purpose
is very, very common. You hear this a lot.
Um, soul, like this whole
like your human soul,
like your human soul
is spelled differently.
S oh, at least. So you're talking about the
one thing. One only. Yeah. So my soul love,
I only have one love,
my sole pair of shoes.
I only have one pair of
shoes. So it's one thing.
One. But the sole purpose. So the only
reason that this industry exists is what?
For monetary gain. So
monetary monetary, you might
have heard of the
international monetary fund.
Exactly. The IMF. And so monetary refers
to money, money, as the, uh, the door said,
it's again. And the gain,
which means basically
means making it to, to
get more money. Yeah.
So that's the point that
this person is making
that, that the sole purpose
of the gambling industry
is to make money. Ouch.
So he's saying, there's
no other reason to
gamble. People are in this
industry just to make
money. It's greedy.
Well, I mean, uh, basically
you could probably say that
almost about almost all
the, all the companies, right?
What about education
companies? That's different.
Education is very
different. Absolutely.
So what's another industry
that has a sole purpose?
Uh, for example, nonprofit organizations,
their sole purpose is to help people.
All right. Okay. I can
get into that. Yeah. Cool.
So, uh, sole purpose and
monetary gain, very useful phrases.
But, uh, let's take
another listen
to today's dialogue and I put to you
some of these great, great new words.
Did you hear the status
thinking of legalizing
gambling in our city?
Soon you're going to have
amazing hotels and casinos here, which
would be good for business. Are you serious?
Gambling is a vice
industry built on deception
and fed by the intentional
exploitation of human
weakness for the sole
purpose of monetary gain.
It disgusts me. What
are you talking about?
How does it exploit
people? Well, to begin
with, gambling is
addictive. It ruins marriages,
destroys families, and
bankrupts communities.
Once you're addicted,
it's very difficult to stop.
People have lost their
houses, cars, and have been
left out on the street
after becoming addicted.
Secondly, it exploits because
men become addicted to
gambling most often
because of the action and risk.
Women gamble to escape, and senior citizens
will start gambling for social interaction.
Under age, gamblers
often start gambling on
sports with friends
and then illegal bookies.
Jeez. Now that I think about it, maybe
legalizing gambling isn't such a good idea.
Although, I have been to
Las Vegas, and I didn't become
addicted or anything like
that. You cannot predict
who will become
addicted to gambling.
Now, excuse me, I have a
protest value to organize.
All right, so gambling,
what are you? What are your
opinions about it? Pro,
gambling, or anti-gambling?
Okay, well, here's the
thing. Gambling is a sport.
And it involves money, obviously, but people
also don't, I don't think, should have
other people telling them
how to spend their money
unless they have
some kind of problem.
So, the law doesn't get
involved if you have a drinking
problem until you're
harmful to people around you.
So, I don't think
that it's right for the
government to be able to say less than you
can't gamble because it's your own money.
If it makes you happy, it
makes you happy. Interesting.
Now, we've seen very
specific cities or places where
you can actually
gamble in this way.
You have Monaco, or Las Vegas,
or Macau, more recently, right?
So, very interesting
cities or countries that
have been built on the
gambling industry, which
apparently is a
multi-billion dollar industry.
I'm sorry. I don't know.
What do you think?
Are you against gambling?
Are you foregambling?
I mean, is it one of those
things that you can really...
Or do you maybe even
like it? Maybe some people
don't even really care
for it. They don't find it
fun to play Blackjack or go to the... play
a round of poker or something like that.
Well, that's their
problem. I enjoy it.
That is fun. I mean, as
long as... with anything,
you do it in moderation. I mean, if you
don't do it too much, I think it's okay.
All right. So, listeners come
to our website, englishpod.
com to the comments section where you
can tell as well, what are your opinions?
If you do, like gambling,
tell us what game you like.
So, and also, if you
have any questions or
comments, we're always
there to answer them, right?
It can be kind of a
big issue to talk about,
because some people are
really against it and some
people are against it. So,
curious to hear your opinion.
Yeah, we look forward to your opinions, and
we'll see you guys later. Bye. Bye. Bye.